ILGWU Paintings, Photographs, and Memorabilia 5780/098 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Paintings, Photographs, and Memorabilia
1965-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/098 MB
3.22 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents), memorabilia.
This collection contains correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to the Political Department's lobbying activities in Washington, D.C. Also contained in this collection are letters and receipts documenting campaign contributions, alphabetical files on states, as well as files on local unions, joint boards, and regional departments. The records of the Political Department also contain ephemeral printed material relating to political campaigns, including pamphlets, posters, and fliers.
5493155
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: All 5780 Collections
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Carey, Hugh L.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Dubrow, Evelyn; Fiene, Ernest, 1894-1966; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924; Green, William, 1872-1952; Loeb, Mitchell; Schlesinger, Benjamin, 1876-1932; Sigman, Morris, 1880-1931; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977; Wells, David; AFL-CIO; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Collectibles; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Labor Federation of Jewish Workers; National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board (U.S.)
5493155
- 4 paintings stored in upright container (see listing) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Morris Sigman painting; Benjamin Sclesinger painting; David Dubinsky, black and white drawing; President Louis Stulberg painting
- 65 Trees in the Histadruth Forest in the name of David Dubinsky: embellished metal frame and announcement (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Testimonial to David Dubinsky: In appreciation of service by Jewish Labor Committee of Chicago (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Sketch of David Dubinsky (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Black and white drawing of President David Dubinsky
- David Dubinsky Awards (Box 4, Folder 1)
  (formerly box 8) -- Presented to David Dubinsky in Deep Appreciation of his role in creating and sustaining the Jewish Labor Committee, November 16, 1973; Resolution of the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations on David Dubinsky…February 16, 1970; United-Italian American Labor Council, Inc. Four Freedoms Award…December 21, 1961; Proclamation, State of New York, Executive Chamber…October 9th, 1979; The General Assembly of the Citizens gathered in extraordinary session unanimously deliberated to confer the title of Honorary Founder…; David Dubinsky is recognized by Gov. Silvio Ascari of the Federazione Unitaria Italiana Lavoratori Abbigliamento (FUILA) for 25 years as President of the ILGWU. June 13, 1957. [In Italian]
- Portrait - unlabeled (Box 4, Folder 2)
  formerly in box 4
- David Dubinsky Plaque from Dress Presser's Union - Local 60, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  formerly box 6 - Likeness of David Dubinsky's face from ILGWU, Local 60, Dress Pressers, by Arturo Sofo, Feb. 22, 1952
- Silver Anniversary TributeDavid Dubinsky: National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board (1961) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  formerly box 7
- Plaque - Presented to David Dubinsky - Honorary President of ILGWUon the occasion of the 30th Anniversary of their Liberation - May 8th, 1945 [New York, May 4, 1975] (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Plaque: The Board of Trustees of Brandeis University Salutes David Dubinsky and names him a Fellow of Brandis University17th day of October nineteen hundred and 56, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Plaque: David Dubinsky You're The Greatest Wilkes Barre Pittston Nanticoke ILGWU Great Dress Strike (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Plaque: Leadership award of the International Rescue Committee to David DubinskyJanuary 27, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Sketches of Morris Sigman and Benjamin Schlesinger (Box 14, Folder 1)